Finding Aid for Kelsey Museum of Archaeology publications, 1976-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Kelsey Museum of Archaeology publications 1976-1998 1976-1990
Kelsey Museum of Archaeology.
0.5 linear ft.
97110 Bimu C450 2
The Kelsey Museum of Archaeology publications collection includes unit and sub-unit publications, as well as exhibit and promotional brochures, flyers, and press releases.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor # 6687 ).
The publications are open for research.
Please consult the history found in the manuscript finding aid that precedes the publications finding aid.
The Kelsey Museum Publications series (.5 linear foot) consists of two subseries: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications. Publications produced by the Kelsey Museum publications include exhibit catalogs, posters flyers and other publicity material, and newsletters.
Subjects:
Kelsey Museum of Archaeology.; Kelsey Museum of Archaeology. Associates.
Contributors:
Kelsey Museum of Archaeology. Associates.; Associates newsletter.; Kelsey Museum newsletter.
Genre Terms:
Bibliographies.; Pamphlets.; Calendars.; Exhibition catalogs.; Press releases.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications subseries includes an undated bibliography entitled The Kelsey Museum of Archaeology Publications. It also contains exhibit and promotional brochures, calendars, flyers, invitations, and press releases. The bulk of publications are exhibition catalogs. They describe exhibits covering a period from 1976 to 1990 with the majority of material from 1976 to 1983. Some of these catalogs have a few black and white photographs, but most have no illustrations. There is also a proposal, dated 1986, presenting the program statement of the Kelsey Museum of Archaeology with a description of the proposed renovation and addition to Newberry Hall where the collection is housed. The Bulletin--Museums of Art and Archaeology which was published jointly by the University of Michigan Museum of Art and the Kelsey Museum of Archaeology from 1978 through 1988 will be found in the: University of Michigan. Museum of Art. Publications.
  - Bibliographies (Box 1)
    - The Kelsey Museum of Archaeology Publications, undated (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Exhibits, 1978-1997 (Box 1)
    - Promotional, 1990-1994 and undated (Box 1)
  - Calendars, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs
    - The Art of Seals: Aesthetic and Social Dynamics of the Impressed Image from Antiquity to the Present, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Crowning Glories: Persian Kingship and the Power of Creative Continuity, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Dangerous Archaeology: Francis Willey Kelsey and Armenia (1919-1920), 1990 (Box 1)
    - The Gods of Egypt in the Graeco-Roman Period, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Greek Sculpture in Transition, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Greek Vases from Boston, c. 600-300 B.C., 1976 (Box 1)
    - In Pursuit of Antiquity, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Karanis, An Egyptian Town in Roman Times: Discoveries of the University of Michigan Expedition to Egypt (1924-1935), 1983 (Box 1)
    - The President’s Choice: A History of the Ruthven Collection, the Collector, and the Donor (1931-1971), 1990 (Box 1)
    - Roman Portraiture: Ancient and Modern Revivals, 1977 (Box 1)
    - A Scientist Views the Past, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Seleucia-on-the-Tigris: An Exhibition of the Excavations at Seleucia, Iraq by the University of Michigan, 1927-32, 1936-37, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Sepphoris in Galilee: Crosscurrents of Culture, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Vaults of Memory: Jewish and Christian Imagery in the Catacombs of Rome, 1981 (Box 1)
    - A Victorian View of Ancient Rome: The Parker Collection of Historical Photographs in the Kelsey Museum of Archaeology, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Wondrous Glass: Reflections on the World of Rome, c. 50 B.C.-A.D. 650, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Flyers
    - 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - 1994-1998, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Invitations, 1982-1995 (Box 1)
  - Press Releases, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Proposals
    - Program Statement Kelsey Museum Renovation and Addition, 1986 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications subseries includes promotional brochures published by the Associates of the Museum. This organization serves as the Kelsey Museum of Archaeology friends group. They also produced the newsletters Associates Newsletter, issued from 1989 to 1993, and Kelsey Museum Newsletter, printed from 1994 to the present.
  - Associates of the Museum
    - Brochures, 1984 and undated (Box 1)
    - Newsletters
      - Associates Newsletter, 1989-1993, 4 folders (Box 1)
        (missing 1991)
      - Kelsey Museum Newsletter, 1994-1997, 4 folders (Box 1)